Nithin Kumar

Front-end developer

Am a skilled Front-end Developer who has around 1 year of experience with Flutter Hybrid Mobile App development. I am comfortable working with React-js, javascript, HTML/CSS, and responsive design to deliver an exceptional user experience. I have proven experience in creating and designing software in a test-driven environment.



26 October, 1998

instagram.com/_shetty_rocks

. 8197412709

in linkedin.com/in/nithin-kumar-854338194

WORK EXPERIENCE

Flutter Developer Dinero

10/2021 - Present Hyderabad

Dinero is a fintech which aims to help young people manage money without hassles.

Roles and Responsibility

- Designed, implemented, and tested Flutter apps using the BLoC pattern for Android and the web.
- Designed and created animated widgets.
- Take part in the Software Development lifecycle.
- Understanding of AWS services.
- Implemented **PWA** (progressive web app) in a native app.
- Integration of third-party API's in a native app.
- Deployment of the app in the play store using CI/CD.
- Integration of SDK like Firebase, Mixpanel and Adjust for analytics and marketing.
- Implementing push notification using AWS SNS and firebase.

Software Engineer InternPagematics LLC

06/2021 - 09/2021

We design, develop and deliver high-tech software solutions to imporve the functionality of business.

Roles and Responsibility

- Desiging and implementing UI components.
- Good understanding of CSS libraries, GIT, Visual studio etc.
- Understanding of REST APIs calls.

EDUCATION

MCA

Manipal Institute Of Technology

01/2019 - 08/2021 8.16 CGPA

BCA

Milagres College Manglore University

04/2016 - 04/2019 72.32% Aggregate

PUC

MGM College Udupi

01/2014 - 06/2016

66.33%

CoursesPCMCs

SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

Online Cab Booking (10/2018 - 04/2019)

- BCA final year project.
- The main idea of the software is to offer the traveling service at a very reasonable price.
- Reduce manpower needed to perform the booking and serving clients.

Hospital Information System (01/2021 - 05/2021)

- HIs are designed for multi-specialist hospitals, to cover a wide range of hospital administration and management processes.
- It deals with collection of patients information like add patient, update, delete, search and view.
- Frontend: HTML,CSS, JavaScript, jQuery.
- Backend: Laravel 6 (PHP Framework), PHP 7.3, MySQL 5.6.45.

LANGUAGES

Professional Working Proficiency

Kannada

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Professional Working Proficiency

Tulu

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Hindhi

INTERESTS

Coding Traveling Volleyball Swimming

Cricket